JOHN R. DAILY

jdaily@me.com

PROFILE

Approaching 30 years of systems management and backend software development experience. Robust troubleshooting, technical leadership, business integration, and technical communications skills.

I have both a deep technical understanding of infrastructure and years of experience as a liaison between business, sales, marketing, and technical personnel.

EXPERIENCE

Associate Director, Virtusa — 2017-Present

Deploy, manage, automate AWS infrastructure supporting patient-facing mobile applications for a large pharmaceutical firm. Integrate Active Directory, ServiceNow, GitHub, AWS for reporting and management tools.

Develop language processing engine in Python for adverse event reports to calculate time-to-onset. Evaluate and develop automated robotic process automation tools.

Senior Software Engineer, Basho Technologies — 2013-2017

Develop Riak KV/TS, distributed NoSQL database software with an emphasis on scale and availability. Mentor new engineers. Write documentation, technical blog posts, and co-author The Little Riak Book. Support customers, sales staff, and developers as technical evangelist.

Solutions Architect, Apparatus — 2004-2013

Software development and systems administration. Deploy mobile device management infrastructure for a Fortune 200 company. Created a WebSphere application deployment engine.

Director of Technology, Progeny Linux — 2000-2004

Served in a wide variety of roles for a tech startup. Technical architecture, project management, sales, Linux kernel programming, web development, technical writing.

Systems Analyst, Eli Lilly — 1999-2000

Consulting Analyst, Software Synergy — 1998-1999

Contracted with, then hired onto, a local pharmaceutical giant. Served as unofficial architect to the enterprise infrastructure division, established the first company-wide LDAP service, architected the Internet infrastructure team's first standardized web platform.

Software Engineer, BBN/GTE Internetworking — 1997-1998

Solaris & Windows administration, NetBSD kernel programming to implement secure routing protocols.

Systems Administrator, Indiana Interactive — 1995-1997

As first technical employee of a startup, was responsible for systems administration and automation of a fast-growing infrastructure, including Solaris, Windows NT, Linux, firewall, and general network administration.

EDUCATION

Engineering & Computer Science at Purdue, IUPUI

Left school before completing my degree to pursue my IT career.

SKILLS

C, Perl, Python, Erlang, Java. Systems and network administration across multiple platforms. Cloud computing, public speaking, technical writing, sales and marketing, technical leadership.